Now just for fun let's try to analyze this graph a little bit.
现在只是为了好玩，让我们试着分析一下这个图表。
Let's take the trends that we can see and talk about what they might mean.
让我们看看我们可以看到的趋势并讨论它们可能意味着什么。
The most obvious thing is that there is that sharp decline and also the fact that in poor countries
最明显的事情是急剧下降，而且在贫穷国家
with a very low GDP the fertility rate is extremely high much much higher than in countries that tend
在 GDP 非常低的情况下，生育率非常高，远高于那些倾向于
to have a higher GDP per capita.
人均GDP更高。
That's quite shocking it's not a small difference almost nine over here and only one or two on the other
这真是令人震惊，这不是一个小差异，这里差不多九个，而另一个只有一两个
side.
边。
Why is that.
这是为什么。
That's the interesting thing that I would want to analyze.
这是我想分析的有趣的事情。
So this is just an example.
所以这只是一个例子。
And notice that I'm going to put phrases in here that make it clear that it's my opinion or I'm just
请注意，我将在此处添加短语，以明确表明这是我的意见，或者我只是
guessing that it's not extra research I'm doing I'm just kind of thinking about it and wondering why
猜测这不是我在做的额外研究我只是在想它并想知道为什么
and I'm using some language in here that lets you know that I am just doing my own analysis and giving
我在这里使用了一些语言让你知道我只是在做我自己的分析并给出
my own opinion since many people in poor countries are Farmers having more children means having more
我个人的看法，因为贫穷国家的许多人都是农民
workers to do manual labor manual laborers often work with your hands like farm work which means the
工人从事体力劳动 体力劳动者经常像农活一样用手工作，这意味着
farm can be more successful.
农场可以更成功。
That means I'm guessing I'm guessing that in countries that are poor maybe people want to have more
这意味着我猜我猜在贫穷的国家也许人们想要更多
children because if they have more children those children can work and if they can all work then the
孩子，因为如果他们有更多的孩子，这些孩子就可以工作，如果他们都可以工作，那么
farm can be more successful just guessing.
只是猜测，农场可能会更成功。
I think the fertility rate is also high due to poor living conditions and insufficient insufficient
我觉得生育率也高是因为生活条件差，不够不够
means not good enough not sufficient sufficient means it's enough it's enough sometimes if something
表示不够好 不够好 表示足够 有时如果某事
is enough we say well that's sufficient although that's quite formal insufficient not enough due to
够了，我们说得好，这就够了，虽然这很正式 不够 不够，因为
insufficient basic health care and nutrition in third world countries third world countries we're usually
第三世界国家的基本医疗保健和营养不足 我们通常是第三世界国家
talking about countries that are quite poor.
谈论相当贫穷的国家。
So I know that in many third world countries in some places not all places there are poor conditions
所以我知道在许多第三世界国家，在某些地方，并非所有地方的条件都很差
living conditions.
生存现状。
And in fact maybe people are hungry sometimes starving sometimes there is disease and because maybe
事实上，也许人们饿了，有时饿了，有时有疾病，因为也许
Babies can't eat enough or there's no basic health care you have high mortality which is very sad.
婴儿吃不饱或没有基本的医疗保健，死亡率很高，这很可悲。
But again I'm just guessing here.
但我只是在这里猜测。
I'm just guessing that because because high mortality is caused by the poor living conditions maybe
我只是猜测，因为高死亡率可能是由恶劣的生活条件造成的
women need to have more children to compensate.
妇女需要生更多的孩子来补偿。
So if you have high mortality then maybe you need to have more babies to meet to that and balance it.
因此，如果您的死亡率很高，那么也许您需要更多的婴儿来满足并平衡它。
We can say compensate to compensate for something is if you have too much of this you need to do more
我们可以说补偿来补偿某些东西，如果你有太多，你需要做更多
of this just to make it balanced.
这只是为了使其平衡。
OK.
好的。
I think the fertility rate is also high due to poor living conditions and insufficient basic health
我认为由于生活条件差和基本健康不足，生育率也很高
care and nutrition in third world countries.
第三世界国家的护理和营养。
It tells me again this is a phrase that lets you know it's my opinion.
它再次告诉我，这是一个让你知道这是我的观点的短语。
It tells me that infant mortality is high.
它告诉我婴儿死亡率很高。
So I'm just saying in many cases young babies infants die because they don't have enough nutrition.
所以我只是说，在许多情况下，年幼的婴儿婴儿死亡是因为他们没有足够的营养。
Tells me that infant mortality is high.
告诉我婴儿死亡率很高。
Women need to have more children just to compensate.
女性需要更多的孩子来弥补。
It's really tragic tragic means.
真是悲剧的悲剧手段。
It's very sad it's a terrible thing.
非常可悲，这是一件可怕的事情。
Perhaps in developed countries developed countries are countries that maybe have a higher standard of
也许在发达国家发达国家是可能有更高标准的国家
living or maybe a higher GDP per capita perhaps in developed countries like Canada or the UK.
生活在加拿大或英国等发达国家，或者人均GDP可能更高。
The average number of children per woman is low due to the high cost of raising and educating children.
由于抚养和教育孩子的成本很高，每个妇女的平均孩子数量很少。
Now that one I can say more confidently.
现在，我可以更自信地说。
I mean I can still use the word perhaps perhaps lets you know that it is a guess and that's just my
我的意思是我仍然可以使用这个词也许让你知道这是一个猜测，这只是我的
opinion.
观点。
Notice I'm using things like I think and perhaps and it tells me to give you a feeling of yeah this
请注意，我正在使用我想的东西，也许它告诉我给你一种感觉，是的
is just my view my opinion.
只是我的看法我的看法。
But still I can be a little more confident about that end thing because I can see it around me right.
但是我仍然可以对最终的事情更有信心，因为我可以正确地看到它在我周围。
I know how expensive it is to have kids here.
我知道在这里生孩子有多贵。
You have to send them to school and it's cost a lot of money.
你必须把他们送到学校，而且要花很多钱。
OK.
好的。
So the average number of children per woman is low due to because of the high cost of raising and educating
因此，由于抚养和教育成本高昂，每个妇女的平均孩子数量很少
children.
孩子们。
OK so that's just one way to analyze when you're doing the analysis.
好的，这只是您进行分析时的一种分析方法。
I would recommend using those phrases to show that it is subjective and don't just state your opinion.
我建议使用这些短语来表明它是主观的，而不仅仅是陈述您的意见。
Make sure you're referencing the data you're referencing the graph you're talking about countries with
确保你引用的数据是你所引用的图表你正在谈论的国家
a low GDP.
国内生产总值低。
Countries with a higher GDP you're talking about what you've just described and having that link is
您所说的 GDP 较高的国家，您刚才描述的内容是
very important because if there is no link or connection between your analysis and the original data
非常重要，因为如果您的分析与原始数据之间没有联系或联系
and the graph then people might begin to feel confused.
然后人们可能会开始感到困惑。
So maybe this is a little bit difficult but I encourage you to try this out a few times.
所以也许这有点困难，但我鼓励你尝试几次。
And if you get used to it I think you'll find that it's actually interesting to try to analyze graphs
如果你习惯了，我想你会发现尝试分析图表实际上很有趣
and see why is it this way.
看看为什么会这样。
Why is this data like this.
为什么这个数据是这样的。
Also if you can describe this clearly you will be the hero at meetings.
此外，如果你能清楚地描述这一点，你将成为会议上的英雄。
You'll be able to clearly communicate things that might not be that easy for some other people to communicate
你将能够清楚地传达一些其他人可能不太容易传达的东西
and that will make you a very powerful speaker as always of course it's very important to practice and
这将使你成为一个非常有影响力的演讲者，当然，练习和练习非常重要
practice makes perfect.
熟能生巧。
Good also say perfect practice makes perfect.
好也说熟能生巧。
What I'd like you to do is find a graph or some sort of data visualization based on your interest or
我希望你做的是根据你的兴趣找到一个图表或某种数据可视化，或者
based on your career perhaps and then describe it describe the data points.
也许基于你的职业然后描述它描述数据点。
Talk about what the whole thing looks like.
谈论整个事情的样子。
And again imagine that you're talking to someone who cannot see it then give a simple analysis.
再次想象您正在与看不到它的人交谈，然后进行简单的分析。
Make sure to use subjective phrases to show that it's your opinion but also make sure to reference things
确保使用主观短语来表明这是您的意见，但也要确保参考事物
from the graph or the chart or whatever it is you're looking at.
从图表或图表或您正在查看的任何内容。
Practice this record it and then go back and listen to it and see if you can correct yourself.
练习这个录音，然后回去听它，看看你是否能纠正自己。
Good luck.
祝你好运。
I'll see you in the next lesson.
我们下节课见。